<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Seikiatsu</title>
    <description>Welcome to Seikiatsu. Kia&apos;s diary about her seikatsu in Japan.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 15:27:25 +0900</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 15:27:25 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Retreat to Kamakura</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to Kamakura for a small retreat from my busy Tokyo life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-first-day&quot;&gt;The First Day&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These few days, the things I need to do and the things I want to do piled up so my mind is so cluttered, making me feel blue. I knew I was gonna burn up anytime soon if I don’t take a break. I didn’t wanna burn out so, to re-organize my thoughts and refresh my mind, I applied for some of my paid leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, I decided to go to Kamakura, which I’ve already visited in the past. I usually want to visit places where I haven’t visited but let me tell you why I chose Kamakura. There are three main reasons. First, Kamakura’s location is not that far from where I live. It just takes an hour to go there. This trip is quite abrupt so I didn’t wanna spend much money so I decided to save on transportation expenses. Second, I chose Kamakura for its vibe. It seems to be a very peaceful place with plenty of temples. It being spiritual suits my current situation, I thought. I’m not a religious person but I like the idea of cleansing one’s soul. The third reason is that Kamakura is situated near the sea. I don’t see seas often so I wanted to go to one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally arrived at Kamakura. I kept my earphones away so I can keep my mind distraction-free&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/0.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting out of Kita-Kamakura station, I saw my first temple of the day, Engakuji.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(By the way, “ji” or “tera” or “dera” means “temple” in Japanese. I feel iffy typing “Engakuji Temple” even though that’s probably the official(?) English translation, because it literally means Engaku-temple Temple)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entrance had a fee so I decided not to go in and just look from the outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked towards my next stopover, Kenchoji, following the signs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hiking course that I planned to take was inside Kenchoji so I had no choice but to enter it, even though it was paid. The temple ground was pretty vast. However, because it was a weekday, there were only very few people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the map, I stumbled upon this remarkably long path. This scene feels like a gate to heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw a few caves while walking. Although I wasn’t sure if I could enter them, they made me excited as they reminded me of my favorite game, Tomb Raider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so intrigued by these statues. I didn’t know what they are but they remind me of angels from Christianity(?) because of their wings. Their whole composition made me feel like they were a mixture of Japan’s tradition and Western. Upon checking on Google, I found out that they were tengu, supernatural beings in Japanese folklore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/10.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/11.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the viewing deck of Hansobo, the heart of Kenchoji.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look close, you can see the sea from afar. I like the fact that I was able to capture temples, forests, hills, and the sea all in one picture. Isn’t it amazing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/12.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/13.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entrance to the hiking course was somewhat blocked so I thought it was closed. Thankfully, the person from the temple shop called out to me and told me that only parts of the hiking trail were closed. Well, I planned to just do some parts of the trail and head to Kamakura station so I proceeded and she let me enter the trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started climbing the hiking course, I saw Mt. Fuji’s iconic white top. The sky was not clear so that part looks like it was floating. Can you spot it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/14.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’m hiking, let me tell you why I enjoy it a lot. When I was still in grade school, I used to play Tomb Raider a lot. I wanted to be like the main character in the game, Lara Croft because she is so strong and adventurous. She often went outdoors to hike and camp, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw a fellow hiker. Japanese hikers are generally friendly so we greeted each other Konnichiwa!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He told me that he can see Mt. Fuji from where he was standing. I already knew I could see Mt. Fuji but he convinced me to go to where he was standing. I went and realized what he was talking about. Mt. Fuji was placed directly on top of the rock, and it was such a good frame to capture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/15.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hiking-thoughts&quot;&gt;Hiking thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While I was hiking, I started to take notice of the minute things again. For example, as the wind blew, I heard the sound of the rustling leaves. Noticing small details of nature like this made me feel the beauty of living in the world.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hiking is free of distraction, that’s why I like it so much. Being in nature is an escape from the busyness of my city life. I feel refreshed by basking in the green forest. This is the feeling of Shinrin-yoku (a Japanese term for forest bathing). I started having doubts about why I chose to live in such a busy city like Tokyo when I prefer a more laid-back place.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I feel grateful living in Japan. First, it is very commuter-friendly. I can easily commute to places such as this without needing a car. Second, because it is not a tropical country, I can do physical activities like hiking without suffering from the heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maybe I also like hiking because it makes me feel closer to death. One wrong step and I could fall and land somewhere inaccessible and no one may know it. So, it means that I could die without anyone knowing. However, I think that being close to death makes me value my life more because I am reminded that I am merely human and not an eternal being. So I want to cherish the time that I have when I’m still alive. It makes me question whether the things I’m doing now are fulfilling my life. Because I only have one life, and after all, I’m a “being towards death”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hiking also makes me feel like I’m in such a huge world because the scenery is so different from my everyday life. And this feeling of being a small entity in an enormous place, such as the world, is not something I feel in my daily life. Suddenly, all my problems and stressors feel so small and insignificant in this huge world. This thought comforts me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve also noticed that there are many older people in this hike. It’s just an amazing thing for me that Japanese elder people are still very strong and healthy that they can do hiking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I passed by this small climb with a rope. Even though it’s such a small thing, it excited me a little because it feels a bit more adventurous. It made me wish I could go to a more adventurous place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/16.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw this lovely hiking couple. Because I wanted to just relax, and not think about navigating myself, I just followed them. Seeing them made me want to have a partner whom I can hike with, even as we grow old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/17.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the end, there were some bamboo groves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/18.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing my fairly short hiking course, I visited Kakuonji (temple) which is situated near the end of the trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/19.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/20.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/21.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/22.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While walking towards Kamakura station, I saw these yellow flowers in bloom, called Wintersweet (ろうばい). They look like yellow cherry blossoms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/23.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;late-lunch&quot;&gt;Late Lunch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was hungry when I finished the long hike and walk. As my holiday treat, I went to a fairly highly rated Japanese restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/24.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ate this and it tasted good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some other photos I took while walking around Kamakura.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/25.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring is about to come!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/26.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/27.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the statues are wearing a mask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heading-towards-my-lodging&quot;&gt;Heading towards my lodging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hostel is located in Hase Station, a few stations away from Kamakura station via the Enoden line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived at my hostel and had a great chat with the friendly hostel owner, Hide-san. He had several recommendations for things to do or restaurants to eat at. And that includes going to Hasedera. I already went to some temples in the morning so I was hesitant to go to another one. However, I still went because I didn’t have anything to do anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hasedera&quot;&gt;Hasedera&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After arriving at the temple grounds and spending a few minutes, I realized that I didn’t regret my decision to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the main hall, the Buddha is not the usual one. It’s gold and huge. I wanted to take a picture but sadly it was prohibited to take photos inside the main hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/28.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/29.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a statue of Amitabha, the Buddha of Limitless Light, in the hall beside the main hall. It is not as big as the main one, but still majestic nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also intrigued by the small statues surrounding one of the halls of Hasedera. Apparently, they are called Sentai Jizo, which means a thousand Jizo’s. According to the guide, Jizo is a Buddhist deity for protecting children and giving prosperity to one’s descendants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/30.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t noticed but when I shared this photo to my friend, he noticed that each face was different from each other. Amazing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the top of the temple grounds and approached the viewing deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/31.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see the town and the sea. It was such a spectacular view. While admiring it, I felt solitude too because there were no other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw some plum blossoms in bloom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/32.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Japanese gardens or temple grounds relaxed me because of wabi-sabi, a form of traditional Japanese beauty which accepts transience and imperfection. I like the concept because it eases my perfectionism, relieving the pressure on things to be perfect. That pressure is lifted as I walk through this garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/33.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to the east of the temple grounds and proceeded to this cave with a tori gate in front. Inside it was so solemn and I felt awe in this very spiritual place.  Few people were praying inside. The temple closed shortly after I exited the cave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/34.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dinner&quot;&gt;Dinner&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my visit to Hasedera, almost everything was closed, so I decided to go to the Izakaya (a Japanese bar) recommended by Hide-san called Shamoji.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/35.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m beside the sea, so it’s just natural for me to eat seafood. I ordered Misaki maguro (tuna) rice bowl with shirasu (whitebait) toppings. Eating this reminds me of the time I went to Misaki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/36.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/37.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fish was fresh as I expected. And I felt full from my rice bowl. So I decided to walk it off before heading back to my hotel. Without realizing it, I reached Kamakura station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/38.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked so much today and I don’t want to arrive at my hotel too late at night, so instead of walking, I decided to take the Enoden line train to Hase station again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived at my hotel quite tired. But, I maximized my day so I won’t complain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-second-day&quot;&gt;The Second Day&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought that since Kamakura is facing East, where the sun will rise, I wanted to see it for myself. I was picking where I want to greet the sun: at the top of a hike, or by the sea while running. I was already tired last night and I didn’t have the energy to look for a trail anymore, so I decided to just go for a run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up around 5:30 am. I drank the free coffee provided by the hostel to energize myself for my run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went outside when it was still dark and started running along the seaside. I loved the sound of the waves and the fresh air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t run seriously, as I was distracted by the beautiful view. I sometimes paused to take videos or photos, which I will dump on this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first stop was Inamuragasaki, a cape not so far from my hostel. I went down to the rocks beside the sea to get a closer view. The waves were roaring as they crashed upon the rocks. I even got showered a bit, which made me laugh. It was so fun yet so calming. I loved the feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/39.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was running towards Enoshima, the sun finally peeked out, so I observed it and snapped a few pictures. The orange rising sun contrasts well with the blue sea. Its light was even reflected by the sea. I felt like I really am in Japan, as I am in the “land of the rising sun,” haha. The view (and the run) was breathtaking, and I felt so lucky to be able to witness a beautiful scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/40.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some pictures from my run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/41.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/42.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enoshima from afar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued running and finally reached Enoshima Ohashi, a bridge towards Enoshima. I wasn’t intending to go to the actual island but I thought since I’m already here, might as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/43.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran from the entrance of Enoshima towards the back part, where the Iwaya Cave is. The island was almost empty because it was an early morning of a weekday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/44.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached the distinct red bridge that leads towards the caves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/45.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the cave doesn’t open until 9 am so I wasn’t able to go in. But it’s okay, I went there twice last year anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran back towards the nearest Enoden station and went back to my hostel to check out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/46.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started heading home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was hungry so I stopped by Kamakura station for brunch. I ate at a cafe called Garden House. I liked its refreshing vibe. Because I was quite hungry, I ordered a salad to add to my open-faced chicken sandwich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/47.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I went back to Tokyo for real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crowd increased as I neared Tokyo. When I finally get off my train, it was pretty crowded. I forgot for a while that Tokyo is a very populated place.  It pricked my heart a bit to be reminded of the busyness of city life. It made me think whether I would rather live in the suburb or provincial place, sacrificing convenience over laid-backness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I arrived home, it felt like I was gone for a very long time. I think it means that I made full use of my two days one night holiday. I did many things, and I was alone. Being alone with my thoughts the whole time, helped me hear my intuition/my heart, which I probably neglected recently. That being said, I think my very cluttered brain came home more organized. In a sense, I fulfilled the purpose of taking a paid leave.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>/kamakura-enoshima/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kamakura-enoshima/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My First Japanese Calligraphy Experience</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I experienced Japanese calligraphy (shodo) for the first time last Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like writing by hand but up until now, I haven’t held a real calligraphy brush so I was excited to join this workshop. Both my friend Yoshiki-san and I wanted to do a new year-ish activity so we thought it would be nice to do Kakizome, the Japanese term for the first writing of the year. Yoshiki-san kindly invited me to this workshop and he registered online for both of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;workshop-day&quot;&gt;Workshop Day&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to eat lunch together before the workshop so we met at Azabujuban Station around an hour before. We ate at a nearby cafe, with a pretty good vibe I liked. The matcha that I ordered tasted better than the one I make at home so I savored it well. As usual, it was fun chatting with Yoshiki-san.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked a bit and we reached a place called エナジーテラスSunnyGo!. It had an art gallery in an underground room roughly as small as my apartment. Though it was small, the atmosphere was lively and colorful, making the cafe I visited earlier pales in comparison. That’s mostly because of the calligrapher’s vibrant art pieces hung all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-26-first-shodo/展示.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Exhibit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-calligrapher&quot;&gt;The Calligrapher&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The calligrapher’s name is Kisen Kuzuya. Based on what I saw in the art gallery, there’s no doubt that Kisen-san is highly-skilled and passionate about Japanese calligraphy (shodo). She said that apart from her main job at an IT company, she makes time to do shodo, explaining that it is not a “side job” but rather a “double job.” (In Japanese, the word for side job is 副業 or fukugyo. Changing the first Kanji or Chinese character to 複, the meaning changes to “multiple jobs” while retaining the reading. Nice wordplay, right?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was deeply moved by that explanation. Kisen-san knowing what she wants and actually doing it inspired me a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;shodo-experience&quot;&gt;Shodo Experience&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said above, I had no prior experience with shodo. So naturally, I was nervous at first. Thankfully, Kisen-san explained the process starting from the basic things, such as explaining the tools used for shodo, how to dip the brush, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It felt nice when I started writing. I fell in love with the feeling of painting the Kanji on the special calligraphy paper. It’s my first time so the character that I wrote was out of balance and kind of looked bad. Kisen-san kindly taught me how to improve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-26-first-shodo/希望.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Learning shodo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One example that I remember is when she taught me that one part of the word for “hope” needed to be curved and not straight as I wrote it to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it was my first time, the creative part of my brain was definitely stimulated. I love the feeling of being creative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-special-present&quot;&gt;A Special Present&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the workshop ended, Kisen-san reminded us that the workshop admission that we had included a present from her. That is, a kanji which Kisen-san thinks represents the participant written by herself on a small card. When Kisen-san was about to write the kanji, all three of us gathered around her. At first, she chose to write the kanji for me first. We tried to guess what she was about to write. When she started writing, the room filled with our oohs and ahhs as we were amazed by her technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Kanji for me was “楽”, which can mean fun or ease. I enjoy my life, so I think it suits me well. And recently, I wanted to feel at ease, so it’s perfect. Yoshiki’s was was “繋”, meaning to connect. The reason is that Yoshiki-san often contacted Kisen-san before this event was held.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took a picture with Kisen-san, holding our presents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-26-first-shodo/プレゼント.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our present&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kisen’s kanji is truly a work of art. I couldn’t wait to decorate my home with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I enjoyed experiencing Japanese culture such as shodo. Thanks to the calligrapher Kisen-san’s bubbly personality, we also felt cheerful. I learned many things about shodo, making me want to write more kanji characters in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>/first-shodo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/first-shodo/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Culture</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spending my winter holidays in Nagano</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to spend my holidays in a snowy place so I went to Nagano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-day-before&quot;&gt;The Day Before&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;前日準備できました！バッグが結構大きいのでカメラバッグも中に入れました。写真のとおり荷物の横にあるブーツは2年ぶりに使うからすごく楽しみにしています。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/前日-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;バッグ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ということで、2年ぶりに雪が多い場所に行くから覚悟するために明日の天気予報を調べてみました。すごく寒いから少し緊張しています。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/前日-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;天気予報&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;明日の出発は6時なのでアラームを5時に設定しておきました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/前日-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;アラーム&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;一日目&quot;&gt;一日目&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;出発です! まだ暗いですが一日を満喫するため早く到着しようと思っていました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/一日目-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;電車&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;まずは参加者と上野駅の新幹線ホームで集合します。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;電車で思ったこと&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;完全に忘れてましたが本日は平日なんです! 満員電車にびっくりしないはずなのに…。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;上野駅から新幹線に乗った&quot;&gt;上野駅から新幹線に乗った&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;友達とやっと会えました。券売機で買いたかったのですが、私はモバイルSuicaを使っているので、suicaのカードを持っていません。結局、新幹線のみどりの窓口で買いました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/上野駅-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;新幹線ホーム&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/上野駅-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;新幹線ホーム&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;友達の紹介&quot;&gt;友達の紹介&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;名前：ブライアン・ラオ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ニックネーム：ブライ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/友達の紹介-00.png&quot; alt=&quot;私とブライ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ブライは母校のアテネオのプログラミング授業の教師でした。彼が奈良先端科学技術大学院大学で大学院と博士課程を卒業しました。今年東京に引っ越して私と同じ種類の仕事のソフトウェアエンジニアとして働いています。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;新幹線の雑談&quot;&gt;新幹線の雑談&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;フィリピンと日本の視野&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;二人はフィリピンに生まれ育って来日しました。フィリピンと日本の視野についてディスカッションしました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;カメラレンズの試しと説明&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/カメラレンズ-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;カメラ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ブライがカメラガチなのでレンズをたくさん持っていて1個を私の基本のミラーレスのカメラに合わせて貸してくれました。その1個のレンズでカメラの機能を説明してくれました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;長野駅到着&quot;&gt;長野駅到着&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;新幹線だとあっという間に長野に到着しました。東京より寒かったです。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/長野駅-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;長野駅&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;杉玉について勉強になった&quot;&gt;杉玉について勉強になった&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;朝食を食べる場所を探していてブライが私を呼び止めました。緑色の玉を指してそれが造り酒屋を現すと説明してくれました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;朝食神戸屋キッチン&quot;&gt;朝食@神戸屋キッチン&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ホットサンドがセットで注文しました。旅行でも野菜を摂るのは欠かせないのでサラダがあってよかったです。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/杉玉-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;杉玉&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;湯田中駅に向かう&quot;&gt;湯田中駅に向かう&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;バスか電車か選べましたが、私はバスが苦手なので、電車で行くことにしました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/湯田中駅に向かう-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;湯田中駅に向かう&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;駅でスイカ使えないことにびっくりしました。また券売機を使いました(☉｡☉)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/湯田中駅に向かう-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;湯田中駅に向かう&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;電車の床が濡れていることにも不思議だと思いました。やっぱり雪が多いと乗客の靴が濡れているんですね。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;湯田中行の電車と乗り換えタイミングで以下の写真を撮りました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/湯田中駅に向かう-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;湯田中駅に向かう&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;景色は土地と山が雪で覆われていました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/湯田中駅に向かう-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;湯田中駅に向かう&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ホステル到着&quot;&gt;ホステル到着&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;お部屋はシンプルな和室です。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/ホテル-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ホステル&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;外はこんな感じで和風をもっと感じました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/ホテル-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ホステル&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ランチ&quot;&gt;ランチ&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ホステルの後ろにある中華そば屋さんでチャシューめんを食べました。たくさん歩くつもりなので高炭水化物は必要だと思いました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/ランチ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ランチ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;満腹でした!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;地獄谷野猿公苑&quot;&gt;地獄谷野猿公苑&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ランチ後は温泉に入っている猿さんたちの地獄谷野猿公苑という場所に向かいました。山道を歩きました。どこでも見たのは雪が積もっている真っ白な景色でした。すごくきれいでした。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/地獄谷野猿公苑-00.png&quot; alt=&quot;地獄谷野猿公苑の歩き道&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;厚い雪に積もった道も歩くことができました。新雪なので粉のように柔らかいです。あとは、以外と観光スポットなのに誰もいませんでした。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/地獄谷野猿公苑-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;地獄谷野猿公苑の歩き道&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;長く歩いて、やっと地獄谷野猿公苑に到着しました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;猿たちが温泉に入らないで周りに座ったり歩いたりしています。たぶん猿はいつも温泉にいるから飽きているかもしれません。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/地獄谷野猿公苑-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;地獄谷野猿公苑&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;数分後についに猿が一匹入りました。観光客はみんな喜んでいました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/地獄谷野猿公苑-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;地獄谷野猿公苑&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;その上に、下記の写真のとおりに二匹の猿がやりました。ブライによると、この写真は「完璧な写真」だそうです（笑）&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/地獄谷野猿公苑-04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;地獄谷野猿公苑&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;地獄谷野猿公苑からホステルまでまた歩こうとしました。ラーメンがもう消化されたのでお腹すいていました。運良くカフェを見つけました。カフェの照明が冬の景色と美しい対照をなすと思って写真を取ってみました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/ココアのお店.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ココアのお店&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ホットチョコレートを注文しました。冬といえばホットココアですね? ( ꈍᴗꈍ) 飲んだから寒い雪の山道を乗り切れるようになります!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/ココア.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ココア&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;湯田中温泉&quot;&gt;湯田中温泉&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;泊まっているホステルがよろづやという温泉と提携しているのでお得な割引を提供してくれました。その切符を購入してよろづやに向かいました。ホステルから歩いて5分で超便利ですね。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/湯田中温泉-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;温泉&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/湯田中温泉-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;温泉&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;よろづやの上品で伝統的なインテリアが気に入りました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/湯田中温泉-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;よろづや&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/湯田中温泉-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;よろづや&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;露天風呂に入って積もった雪を見ました。残念ながら雪が降らなかったけど、雪景色の中で入るお風呂は最高でした。ほぼ一日中使っていた足が温泉の熱さのおかげでリラックスできて回復されました。疲れた後の温泉は最高ですね〜&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ブライはこのくらい温泉で幸せでした。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip//湯田中温泉-04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;温泉で幸せ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;居酒屋で夕食&quot;&gt;居酒屋で夕食&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;温泉から出たのはもう遅いのでほぼすべてのレストランがもう閉店していました。結局まだ開いている居酒屋に食べに行きました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/居酒屋-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;居酒屋&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ブライアンはアルコールアレルギーで、私もアルコールの頻度を減らしたいので二人は居酒屋でソフトドリンク飲んじゃいました。オレンジジューズとサイダーで乾杯したのは面白いと思います。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/居酒屋-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ソフトドリンク&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;焼き鳥食べました〜しょっぱすぎてオレンジジューズを注文したのはありがたいです(笑)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/居酒屋-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;焼き鳥&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;焼きおにぎりを食べたことないので食べました。なぜ茶色かわからなくて玄米だと思っていて超ヘルシーな居酒屋メニューだと思いました。ブライがそれは玄米じゃなくて醤油の効果だよって説明してくれました。間違えましたね(；^ω^）&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/居酒屋-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;焼きおにぎり&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;二日目&quot;&gt;二日目&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;奥志賀高原スキー場&quot;&gt;奥志賀高原スキー場&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;湯田中駅から奥志賀高原までこのお得な赤いチケットでバスを乗りました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/奥志賀高原-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;奥志賀高原へのバス&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;雪の山が綺麗ですね〜これは東京から全然見えない景色なんです。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/奥志賀高原-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;雪の景色&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;着いたらリフトのチケットを購入してスキーレンタルしました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/奥志賀高原-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;スキーレンタル&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/奥志賀高原-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;スキーレンタル&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/奥志賀高原-04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;スキー地図&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;リフト乗りました。天気がよくてありがたいですヽ(･ˇ∀ˇ･ゞ)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/奥志賀高原-05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;リフト&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;スキースクール、クラスとか受けてないのでスキーのやり方があまりわかりません。他のスキーヤーを見習いながらやってみました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;すごく怯えていましたがやってみたかったです。リフトを降りたらスキーでしか坂を降りられません。その恐怖を少し忘れるようにイヤホンを使いました。陽気な音楽を聴いたらとても恐怖心は和らぎました。音楽に励まされていてわくわくしながら坂を滑り降りました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;一方で、よく自信がなくなりました。転ぶのが怖くてパニックに陥っていました。パニックだから体が硬くなっちゃって結局転んでしまいました。転びすぎて何回転んだかがもう数えられないほど多いです。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;初級の坂なのにこれほどへたくそなのは恥ずかしいですね(^～^;)ゞでも大丈夫ですよー。だれでも最初は初心者だからこの経験は当然です。だって、スキーをした理由はエンジョイするためですから。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;とにかくすごく楽しかったです。転んでも雪がすごく柔らかくて全然大丈夫でした。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;でも、知らないこととか、あまりなれていないことをやれば、頭が疲れますね? 言いたいのはスキーで脳の細胞が死んだように精神的に疲れました(~_~メ)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;渋温泉へ&quot;&gt;渋温泉へ&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;さきのバスチケットは往復なのでそれを使ってバスで山を降りました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/渋温泉へ-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;渋温泉へ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;夕食&quot;&gt;夕食&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;バス停から少し歩いてハッピーレストランに着きました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/ハッピー-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ハッピー&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;うわ～やっと本物の食べ物なんです（朝食はヨーグルト、ランチはカロリーメイトしか食べなかったもの）！とんかつ定食が結構美味しかったです。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/ハッピー-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ハッピーのかつ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;金具屋&quot;&gt;金具屋&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;帰り道に渋温泉の金具屋に見に行きました。金具屋は歴史の宿です。スタジオジブリの千と千尋の神隠しのモデルだそうです。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/金具屋-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;金具屋&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;渋温泉から歩いて帰りました。雪がもう半解凍されていたのですごく滑りやすかったです。気を付けて歩きました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;途中で、この雪で覆われているポストを見ました。私は雪とポストが両方好きで一枚の写真でこの素敵なシーンが撮れるのがいいですね〜さらに真赤なポストは真っ白な雪との対比が綺麗ですね〜&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/金具屋-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ポスト&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;三日目&quot;&gt;三日目&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ホステルをチェックアウトして、湯田中駅に向かいました。電車で長野駅に向かいました。時間を潰したいため本を読みました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/三日目-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;本を読んでいる&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;着いたらちょうどランチタイムでした。ブライが信州そば食べたかったので駅の立ち食いそば屋さんで月見そばを食べました。立ち食いははじめてでした (人 •͈ᴗ•͈)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/三日目-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;月見そば&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;予約したバスの時間になったらバス停に向かいました。なぜ帰るのがバスかの理由は節約したいからですが、休みはリラックスする時間のはずだから、それほど安っぽくしたくないと二人と決めました。往路が新幹線で復路がバスは満足できる妥協だと思いました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/三日目-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;バス&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;バスを乗って本を読み続けました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/三日目-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;本を読んでいる&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;その後は、最後にこのレポートを書き終わらせました。全体的に、それはとても素敵な休暇でした。 今回の旅行は、私が雪の上を歩いた中で最も長い時間だと思います。 フィリピン人として熱帯の国で育ち、雪が降るのを見たことがなかったので、長野のような雪の降る場所に行くととても幸せです。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;校正者：田中大樹&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>/nagano-winter-trip/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/nagano-winter-trip/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
