<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Seikiatsu</title>
    <description>Welcome to Seikiatsu. Kia&apos;s diary about her seikatsu in Japan.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 17:21:40 +0900</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 17:21:40 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lake Tama Cycling Road</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to hike with my friend, Maru, to see flowers. However, as it is still too early for spring, I decided to ask him out on a cycling trip instead. Two birds in one stone I thought. I get to practice my nearly non-existent cycling skills and I get to spend time with Maru.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I am the one who initiated this trip, I had to come up with a rough plan. I don’t mind it at all as I love planning and Maru seems to be relatively open to things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I considered the Tamagawa River (1) cycling route which I found out about while running along said river. The two reasons I did not go with that were 1) I run along Tamagawa around four times a week at this point so I wanted to go somewhere different, 2) there is a long stretch of cherry trees here that haven’t bloomed yet so I decided that cycling here with someone would be better for the next time. So, I googled cycling roads we could go to around Tokyo. The popular ones came out, Edogawa River, Arakawa River, etc. But the thing that caught my eye was the Tama Lake cycling road. The description on Google that sold it to me was something on the lines of “perfect for nature without going too far from the city center.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Maru and I don’t have bicycles but I was rest-assured because I always rent one anyway. However, I found out upon checking out Docomo Bike Share, the app that I use all the time to rent a bike, that there are no renting stations near Tama Lake. So, I had to look up a way to rent a bike, or else we could not go on this trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, there is another mainstream renting service called Hello Cycling. It seems to have a larger scale than Docomo. I downloaded it and found some bicycle stations in Musashi-Sakai Station, the station where we would begin our cycling. I told Maru to install it and he asked me for a coupon code. Apparently, there is an ongoing promo that gives a discount when you invite a friend both you and your friend. Good catch, I thought. Just like that, we were equipped to go on this trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked Maru where his nearest train station was and I was surprised that he answered the station name and its number. I almost never used station numbers so I found it amusing. Considering where he is coming from, I looked for a station where we could meet on the way to our cycling starting point, Musashi-Sakai Station. Then, I drafted a rough timetable and sent it, together with some pointers to consider, to Maru on the day before the big day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-day&quot;&gt;The Day&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before leaving my house, I had a quick call with my Japanese teacher to practice my speaking. We have a practice every Saturday and I was lucky enough that he was willing to accommodate my fairly early schedule this day. I did not feel like eating so I just drank a cafe latte, thinking the caffeine would energize me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the meeting place, Ochanomizu Station, right on time. Maru was gonna be late, he informed me. I did not mind it at all. But that hasn’t always been the case. Back when I was younger, I despised waiting for late people. I thought it was disrespectful to the person waiting and wasteful of time. Thankfully, as my views on life changed, my reaction and attitude toward waiting for the late person also changed. I now see it pointless to have such a negative reaction over something that could not be controlled. Blaming the late person is also pointless. Being late is not always the late person because of the fact that accidents happen. Sometimes even when the person who is late strives to be on time but is just unfortunate to accidentally miss trains, etc. (2) Besides acknowledging the pointlessness of things and the fact that accidents do happen, I also figured out that the time waiting did not need to be a wasted time. Because people being late can’t be fully avoided, I now use the time waiting to entertain myself, like fiddling with my phone. This time, I had my Kindle reader with me so I used it to read the current book that I was reading, What I Talk About When I Talk About Running by Haruki Murakami.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While waiting, I had my second serving of caffeine. I got my energy “booster,” giving me alertness. Despite just being a bottled coffee from the train station convenience store, it was rather tasty. Good purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maru and I met on the train platform and rode the next train bound to our destination. Thanks to the caffeine in me, I felt fully awake and fairly talkative. We had a chat about Joe Hisaishi and how good his music is. He likes Spirited Away’s theme and I like Nausicaa. Mostly because it’s catchy. I don’t remember the song names but I can identify them when I hear them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some time, we arrived at Musashi-Sakai Station. We bought picnic food at the Queen’s Isetan supermarket right outside the ticket gates. The cashier asked Maru if he wanted an &lt;em&gt;oshibori&lt;/em&gt; but he did not understand it so I said yes for him, explaining its meaning after. I guess this kind of word is not something you learn from class but from experience, I thought. As we were putting the sandwiches we bought in our bag, I remembered about the mandarin oranges that I packed in my bag. I was afraid of them being squeezed during our ride, later on, joking that it would turn into orange juice if ever. Maru told me to put it inside a plastic bag provided at the supermarket packing counter so I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked to the Hello Cycling station “as a warm-up,” I told Maru. Not exactly a lie per se but the true agenda was, that I just wanted to start cycling as near as possible to the cycling road. Yes, that’s right, we had to cycle a bit to reach the technical starting point of the cycling road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While walking, I mentioned the song Cold Heart to Maru. It was my earworm at the moment and it was just fascinating to me that it is a song sung by both Dua Lipa and Elton John. Yes, the old Elton John. I was thrilled by the fact that Maru knew about Elton John. Not many young people are familiar with the classics, that’s why. Maru has good taste, I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw some pretty flowers during that walk as well. This is where Maru expressed that he feels like he was already out of Tokyo and I couldn’t agree more. It was still Tokyo but it was already a suburb. I liked the environment here and the weather is in full cooperation, not a single cloud in my sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the Hello Cycling station and picked up our bicycles. Not that we needed to, all of them were almost identical, if not. I walked Maru through how it is done. Truth to be told, it is my first time using Hello Cycling. But because I’ve used Docomo before, I figured that the procedure would be the same. And it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We unlocked our bikes. As a short person, I needed to adjust the saddle and Maru helped me with it. This is how little my experience is—even adjusting the seat height would be needing assistance. On top of that, I tried unparking the bike by pushing the parking support (3) up but it would not budge. Maru explained that there is a lever on the left side of the bike and that I had to push it down first before I can raise the parking support bar (3). So that’s why I have to stay on the left of the bike when walking it, he said. Another fundamental thing I learned. Thanks, Maru.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started riding and I was very nervous. Thanks to the few cycling practices I have done this month, I was less nervous than before but the degree of nervousness was still high. To help me regain my composure, I decided to listen to music via my true wireless earphones. I asked Maru if I could and he said sure, as long as it’s not too loud. Well, it did not matter anyway because I was only going to use one earbud. This scene reminded me of when I went skiing. I fear skiing as well as I have no control over it due to a lack of skills. I wore my earbuds and listened to uplifting music and my fear was effectively reduced by around 50%, allowing me to ski down the slope. Unluckily, my earbud fell and that anxiety relief was short-lived. Hopefully, this time, my earbud wouldn’t fall. I played Cold Heart and was grateful for the ease that music granted me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello Cycling’s bicycle felt lighter than Docomo’s. Maru pointed out that the bike was well-maintained and I couldn’t agree more—it was such a smoother bike than my previously rented ones. At this point, I can say that the only reason why I haven’t used Hello Cycling before is the fact that I didn’t know about it. I was glad that Maru could have a good first experience with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rode the bike through some actual roads before reaching the starting point of the cycling road. It was nerve-wracking to do but it was the only way to reach the starting point and also to learn. I wouldn’t learn unless I face my fears, I told myself. I kept on asking Maru for his patience and understanding of my poor skills but maybe I overdid it as he was very kind and understanding towards my inadequacies. Thank you, Maru.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After crossing a few roads here and there, we finally reached the starting point. What I can see was a long stretch of a road about half the width of the normal one for cars— too small for cars but more than enough for bikes. It’s an actual mini road for bicycles, cute, I thought. There were two lanes, one to go ahead and one to go back. There were plenty of people using the road: runners, joggers, walkers, you name it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the road was a shared place, we could not go so fast. I had to be extra careful because I knew for a fact that I was still a clumsy rider. The last thing I would want to happen was to accidentally hit someone with my lack of control. I was more scared of hitting someone than injuring myself. The start was very slow due to my extra precaution, lack of confidence, and another reason that I found out only later on the ride, which I will mention further in this journal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The road was full of metal barriers to slow the cyclists down, or “obstacles” as I prefer to call them. I can say that they are effective in slowing cyclists down, and they are exceptionally successful in doing so against me. While the average cyclist can pass through these obstacles with ease, the opposite could be said for me. My confidence was almost non-existent so squeezing myself into these small spaces was a tough effort. 90% of the time, if not all of the time, I had to get off my bike and walk through these obstacles due to my fear of cycling through narrow spaces (fear of bumping into things). I’m pretty sure Maru could have passed through these barriers with ease but he was patient enough to cycle behind me, to stop when I had to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loathed the obstacles because they were a hassle to our otherwise straight-line path. These barriers were not visible on the map and so I wasn’t expecting them at all, catching me off-balance (pun &lt;em&gt;intended&lt;/em&gt;) Although I have this negative feeling towards them, I could see their importance in keeping the pedestrians safe, so I accepted the fact that they had to be there. I could complain all I wanted but they wouldn’t magically disappear so I just let it ride (pun &lt;em&gt;intended again&lt;/em&gt;). That being said, I took the opportunity to see how these obstacles can actually be helpful to me instead of being against me. I realized because of the repeated action of stopping, getting off, walking, and riding again, I was subconsciously practicing those skills. I got used to stopping and riding in such a short time span. Everything can be turned into a learning experience, after all, whether it is positive or negative. All I’m sure of is that learning can’t possibly be a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few kilometers of cycling, we passed by a train station, marking the first milestone of this cycling activity. Like most train stations, this one had several restaurants and shops scattered around it. I did not have the chance to use the washroom before starting the ride so I wanted to use the one in the supermarket. I mentioned it to Maru but I took it back, saying that I could still hold it in. I was thinking that I was already slowing Maru down by a lot so if I could just use the toilet at a later time, during an actually planned break, it wouldn’t be as bad. But Maru argued that I shouldn’t hold it back so I just agreed. There was a sign right outside the supermarket saying that parking bicycles weren’t allowed but Maru was gonna stay behind to look after my bike anyway so he waited outside. I tried to be as quick as I could but unfortunately, there was a queue in the ladies’ room, as usual. I felt relieved when I went back to Maru. I’m glad I followed him because I didn’t realize that holding it in was also adding to the mental stress that I had at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We continued to ride and came across a very steep overpass for bikes and pedestrians. It intimidated me big time. At the time of writing this, I don’t remember exactly (4) but I think Maru told me that it is my chance to learn how to ride slopes. He guided me on how to adjust the assistance of our e-bikes. I increased the assistance and felt amazed by it, as I was able to ride over the overpass without much effort. I wasn’t confident about riding back down so did it very slowly, using my bike’s brake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cycled moving forward, encountering more obstacles. Sometimes, I felt confident and passed through them but most of the time, I was too close to bumping them. I told Maru, “I had to swallow my pride and walk (through the obstacles).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes, we decided to stop by a small park for a short break. Since winter was only about to end, the park looked pretty dead. I ate my mandarin for a quick sugar boost. We chatted about growing old, looking at the two passersby whom we didn’t know if they were a couple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We scheduled our next stopover as when we see the lake and continued to cycle. On the road, a white family passed by (this will be relevant later).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maru explained about the bicycle gears. He told me to try switching it. As soon as I did, I felt a significant increase in efficiency with my cycling. I assumed later on that the prompt for this teaching was probably because he saw me struggling to pedal needlessly on the first gear. I’m not complaining, but rather grateful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shifting gears on my bike was just like driving, I thought, as I recall my manual driving memories. From that, I started associating riding a bike with driving. Look ahead, not down, brake slowly, shift gears appropriately, etc. After all, bicycles are just minimalistic cars, in my opinion. With these thoughts and cues, some part of my nervousness went away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon stopping at yet another barrier, Maru exclaimed “did you make that guy fall?” I did not notice if I did, didn’t see nor hear anything. But I wouldn’t be surprised if I actually did. I felt sorry for whoever that guy was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few more couple of obstacles, they’ve finally lessened to a point where I only encountered one or two every five minutes. Same story with the people using the cycling road. Now, this was a game-changer in my cycling experience. Maru and I arrived at the entrance to the park right beside the lake way earlier than we both anticipated. We took around half the time of the first half of the ride. I double-checked the map in disbelief but it was true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second half of the ride to this point was way quicker not only because of the fewer obstacles but also because I was starting to gain a bit of confidence, giving me a sense of control to just keep going on. After the hurricane, comes the rainbow, as Katy Perry said in her Fireworks song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long stretches of no obstacles or people, after the hurricane, comes a rainbow, as Katy Perry said in Fireworks. I definitely deserve some fireworks for reaching here, after all, I have already cycled 13 km up to this point. And for someone who couldn’t ride a bike for a 100m or so without panicking just a month or two before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We paused and took a selfie to celebrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I had some energy left (and maybe Maru as well.) We agreed to “stop when we can stop,” meaning, if there is a place where we can park the bike, we will stop and take a break there. Maru assured me that I can stop anytime I felt like stopping and it was so kind of him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We continued cycling and it went as smoothly as the second half. Though it felt a bit different because the elevation was way more variable than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw a park with some families playing around and decided to stop there. We parked the bicycle in the parking for the park (lol). I was afraid of our bikes being stolen because after all, we just rented them. But we tried locking it, and amazingly, we could. We just had to use the pin to unlock it whenever we want to continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It felt relieving to get off the bike after riding it for quite some time. This is also the time I realized that the hydration I brought with me was not enough, so I purchased another bottle from the vending machine beside the parking. Even though we were far from the city center, I was delighted at the fact that there is a vending machine here to quench my thirst. Japan truly is the land of vending machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked a bit to a gazebo in the park. It felt nice to be finally under the roof. I did not realize that my sun exposure was already probably too much. If I remember correctly, Maru also wanted to rest in a place under a shade. Thankfully the gazebo was empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maru saw this charging port right beside the gazebo. We were so amazed. I’m gonna correct my sentence above, Japan is not only the land of vending machines, but Japan is THE land of convenience. I conveniently charged my phone here out in the boonies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-03-12-cycling-lake-tama/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat down and ate the sandwiches that we brought from the train station. Hooray for recharging, both my phone and my body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We strolled around the park after we ate our lunch. We saw a single blooming tree and of course, I took the chance to take a selfie there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I observed there were plenty of fallen leaves that were piled up all over the park. It was so tempting to jump and fall on them just because they reminded me of Assassin’s Creed (if you know, you know). Sadly Assassin’s Creed is just a game and I’d probably hurt myself trying because of real-world physics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The park consisted of some obstacle courses. If I were fully charged, I would have tried them all but because we were still far from our finish line, I decided to just preserve my energy. But one of the installations piqued my interest, it was the log climb, I climbed it. Maru kindly recorded me doing so. It was a fun experience, it made me feel like I was the badass Tomb Raider herself (although it was totally nothing compared to what she does lol).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking this break in the park not only recharged me physically but also mentally. I was already mentally fatigued by taking on this challenge, I expressed to Maru. He said it’s amazing that I can sustain a mentally challenging state for quite a while and I felt flattered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went back to the parking and thankfully our rented bikes were still there. We unlocked them and continued cycling. The fear of riding was still there but we went so much faster, all thanks to the break we had and the confidence which was slowly building up in me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While riding, my left wrist started getting numb at times. I thought to myself that it was probably due to the mental stress that I had. Even though it was mental, it was getting reflected in my physical stress—my arms, and hands stiffened as a grasped the bicycle’s handle too tightly. Whenever I notice this, I tried to actively loosen up my grip a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing cycling along with the like, I saw the white family that I have mentioned above. They were already on their way back. Wow, we were still on the way and this family, with kids, we’re already on their way back, proved how slow we were due to how bad my cycling skills were, I laughed to myself. Not only that but there were also small kids who overtaken me easily. I wish I had their confidence in riding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were times when I was scared of losing control. And the song being played by my earphones from a random playlist having the lyrics of “I’m losing control” did not help at all. I was terrified of losing control and crashing. But I told myself, maybe I should be stoic about it… resisting death will only make it closer, I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At times when I did not feel like I was out of control, it was actually a good feeling, especially when sliding down. And then I realized that I can finally go down the slope without being crazy scared about it, while staying put on the bicycle, with my foot attached to the pedal. I was not able to do this before, so I felt a bit proud of the small accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were already tired so we decided to wrap our ride up in the nearest Hello Cycling station from our current location. It was stationed beside a Buddhist temple. As soon as I got off my bike, I felt a huge relief. Walking felt amazing, mostly because of the fact that walking does not need mental strain, it does not need controlling, and falling is impossible because I am my body. It made me wonder, maybe cyclists feel like the bicycle is a part of their body, so they may feel in full control?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were already there so we might as well check the temple out. We walked on the temple grounds and saw the bright red pagoda and a cave. Feeling adventurous, I invited Maru to go inside the cave. The inside was cool and windy, perfectly refreshing to me, after a quite long workout. We exited the cave and reached the backside of the pagoda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-03-12-cycling-lake-tama/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw a staircase going down with some interesting architecture to it. It reminded me of the Chinese temple I went to as a kid in Baguio City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-03-12-cycling-lake-tama/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a Kannon Statue pouring an endless stream of water onto a small pond. We also saw a temple surrounded by plenty of pinwheels. It reminded me of how my ex gave me a pinwheel annually when I was in university. It was a good memory so I shared that small detail of my life with Maru.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While checking out the nearest parking earlier, we actually saw that there was a “Totoro Forest” near our current location. I wanted to check it out, and luckily Maru was open to the idea. I let him navigate us. We went back up the dragon guarded staircase, only to find out that it was the wrong direction when we were already at the top. It was funny that we ended up going back down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way, we saw this ring on the map and I was so curious about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-03-12-cycling-lake-tama/5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked near it and found out that the donut hole was actually a shrine, and the donut itself is a circular pond surrounding it, with some plants around it. Interesting, I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking forward, we saw a sign that says thank you for visiting the temple, in Japanese. I explained it to Maru, thinking it was something good to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While strolling in the empty streets, I felt ecstatic, the same feeling as the runner’s high. I thought that maybe it was the endorphins we got from cycling for quite a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw a huge dome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-03-12-cycling-lake-tama/6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started talking to Maru about Strava, which is basically “Facebook for exercising”, I said. I also revealed my goal of cycling 100 kilometers in March to be able to learn how to ride it, and have some confidence in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We passed by a Family Mart and bought a rehydration supply. I realized that I have underestimated the hydration that I needed so I got a huge bottle of Sokenbicha. I drank a lot to rehydrate myself because I lost so much water from sweating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Checking out Google Maps, I just found out that we were already in Saitama. I was thrilled by that fact and declared it to Maru. But he already knew. Apparently, he saw a sign that we were entering Saitama while we were cycling. I did not notice that sign at all because I was too focused on staying in control while cycling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached Totoro’s Forest. According to Google, it is a popular summer hiking place. There were several spots that are numbered, Totoro Forest 1, Totoro Forest 2, etc. I did not understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-03-12-cycling-lake-tama/7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traversing to Totoro’s Forest was unexpected hiking. Maru’s pants did not seem easy to move with. Sorry, Maru, I thought. I took this moment to talk about my previous unexpected hike in Kamakura where I was wearing office clothes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took short breaks from walking and climbing and I sipped my &lt;em&gt;Sokenbicha&lt;/em&gt;. I explained its kanji to Maru and why I like it—it’s refreshing爽, healthy健, and beautiful美 tea茶.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also explained the concept of 森林浴 &lt;em&gt;Shinrinyoku&lt;/em&gt; or forest bathing to Maru. I taught him the kanji and it was funny that there were a lot of tree components in the kanji.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we walked through the forest, there were more and more insects around. I thought it was weird because winter just ended and it wasn’t that warm yet. We came across a signboard while walking and it said that we were in 虫たちの森 &lt;em&gt;mushitachi no mori&lt;/em&gt;, meaning “forest of insects”. That made perfect sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started hearing a trumpet sound while walking inside Totoro’s numerous forests. It was a good and relaxing background music that adds to the shinrinyoku experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw from another map that there was supposed to be a plum grove nearby. I was certain that they were already blooming because plums were already blooming everywhere in the Tokyo / Kanagawa area that I have been to. We walked to where we thought the plum trees were but we were not able to see them because we did not actually take note of the map that we saw…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maru noticed the dead trees and said that those trees were already past their peak. I told him that was not the case as dead trees are not yet in bloom and it was the green trees that are past their peak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We couldn’t find the plum grove so we headed toward the park right beside Sayamako (Lake Sayama). As we walked toward it, the trumpet sound was increasing in volume, indicating that we were nearing it. We arrived at the base of the lake. We had to climb a small hill so that we can see the lake itself. While climbing, Maru saw the trumpet player on the hill, he exclaimed “finally!” I thought the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally saw the lake and it was huge and breathtaking. Not only the lake view was splendid, but also the view facing the opposite direction of the lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-03-12-cycling-lake-tama/8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maru saw the soccer field in the view and mentioned that it was uncommon to see in Japan, as baseball fields were way more popular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-03-12-cycling-lake-tama/9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the lake, there was a long stretch of runway, and Maru said it feels like we were in the Great Wall of China. Both of us haven’t been there though. I even forgot about the existence of the Great Wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked to a resting area and ate snacks. Maru apparently bought two FamiChikis and shared one with me. As I bite into the juicy boneless fried chicken, I realized that I haven’t consumed this delightful treat in quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-03-12-cycling-lake-tama/10.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maru opened up about his studies and I listened to his stories while enjoying our chicken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fatigue was already setting in so we started heading back to the station. The nearest station was Seibukyujo-Mae. It was such a wide station but it was so empty. The train that we were gonna onboard arrived so we secured our seats. The seats were well-cushioned, making them pretty squishy. I appreciated it a lot, and Maru more, because his butt has been hurting from riding the bike for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train started operating and we were finally on our way home. I asked him when was the time he cycled the longest? He answered this trip is the longest one. Me too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun was already setting while we were on the way home. It was a pretty view, I exclaimed. Maru said that I can appreciate small things. I loved what he said because I knew it is true. I think it’s because I write my diary every day, helping me be grateful for the smallest of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought that the sunset signified the end of the day and the end of our trip. It was such a nice trip to the suburb. I definitely wanted to do it again. I wanted to tell Maru but I hesitated, thinking I could say it when I was nearer to my stop. But Maru said it first, and I was happy to say it back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have reached where I needed to transfer trains so I said goodbye and expressed my gratitude to Maru.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few more trains and several more stations, I was able to get home. I unpacked and saw my last piece of mikan. Thank god, it didn’t become juice, I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;Footnote&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) I always feel iffy whenever I type &lt;river_name&gt;gawa River because &quot;gawa&quot; means river in Japanese so when I say Tamagawa River, in my head it goes like &quot;Tama River River&quot;&lt;/river_name&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) that being said, while being understanding toward late people, I still strongly encourage people to strive to be on time because, in the end, it is their responsibility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(3) I don’t know what this is called and Googling bicycle parts did not help&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(4) Writing a journal about an event is best done right after it because any longer than that, I start to forget details&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;acknowledgment&quot;&gt;Acknowledgment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maru: Thank you for your patience and for hanging out with me. I learned a lot from you and it was such a fun experience!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dua Lipa &amp;amp; Elton John: Thank you for your song Cold Heart. Because of your wonderful music, I was able to relieve some of the stress that came with my fear of falling from the bike&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello Cycling: Thank you for enabling us to go on a cycling trip without owning our own bicycles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>/cycling-lake-tama/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/cycling-lake-tama/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>Friends</category>
        
        <category>Cycling</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Girls&apos; Hike at Mt. Maku</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I hiked with my girl friends in Mt. Maku for an early spring!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;start&quot;&gt;Start&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to hike at least once a month so I searched on Google for hiking recommendations for early February. One of the Google Search results showed some hiking recommendations where you can do “hanami 花見,” the Japanese word for watching flowers. Because of that, I included “hanami” in my array of usual Google Search keywords: “hiking”, “day-trip”, “beginner,” plus “hanami”. This article came up in one of the first few results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://yamahack.com/4009&quot;&gt;黄色にピンク色とりどり。低山お花見ハイクで、一足早く春の花を愛でに行こう！&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I skimmed the article and thought that the flowers in the pictures were beautiful. My favorite color is pink so my choices were cherry blossoms, peach blossoms, or plum blossoms. It was not time for cherry and peach, so I went with plum blossoms. In the article, Mt. Maku in Yugawara town has one of the earliest viewing periods so I chose that. According to the article, the plum blossoms are ready for viewing starting early February to mid-March, which is just in time. At first, I scheduled the hike to be on the 12th of February, but due to a previous appointment, I rescheduled it to the next week. However, it rained that day so I ended up going on the 26th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-participants&quot;&gt;The Participants&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, I invited two friends. Let me briefly introduce them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lai&quot;&gt;Lai&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lai from Malaysia came to Japan at the same time as me to work in the same company. She is one of my best friends in Japan whom I hiked with the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hina&quot;&gt;Hina&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hina is one of my first few Japanese friends. We went to a badminton event last month and I thought that it was fun to be active with her and she told me that she likes hiking so I invited her to join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am the organizer for this hike so it was my responsibility to introduce them to each other. I didn’t know the Japanese word for the person who introduces her friends to each other, so I asked my language partner during our language exchange before leaving for the hike. He said that I can use the word is “kanji 幹事.” In other words, I am the “kanji” of this trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/PXL_20220226_002238847.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took this selfie inside the train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a rough draft of the plan for the hike and sent it to both Hina and Lai via SNS. It looked like something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hey, I made a rough plan,  lemme know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;7:45 Depart from Kawasaki Station via the Tokyo-Ueno Line&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;7:45-9 Go to Yugawara Station&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;9~ Convenience store,  toilet break, etc&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;9:30 Go to Mt. Maku via bus&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;10 Slowly start hiking&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;12 Do a lunch picnic somewhere in the mountain&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;14 Finish hiking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;departure-from-kawasaki-station&quot;&gt;Departure from Kawasaki Station&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three of us met in Kawasaki Station as planned. I introduced Lai and Hina to each other. Both of them speak fluently enough Japanese and English so it was fine since there is no language barrier. We departed using the Ueno-Tokyo Line. We chatted about several different topics and thought my two friends can get along with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/Untitled.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were headed towards the direction of Mt. Fuji so we were able to see it huge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/PXL_20220226_001529487.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train line ran along the sea so we were able to see its beauty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;arrival-at-yugawara-station&quot;&gt;Arrival at Yugawara Station&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/Untitled.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As planned, we purchased picnic goods from the convenience store right in front of the station. We were all hungry so each one of us ate an onigiri (Japanese word for “rice ball”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Google Maps, we were supposed to use a bus to go towards Mt. Maku. However, the schedule written on the app was a bit different from the actual one. We figured it out because a lady was announcing the bus departures to Mt. Maku via a megaphone. There is probably a special schedule today as there is an ongoing event in Mt. Maku called the 梅の宴, or the banquet of the plum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were on the bus, I realized that I forgot a very important matter to ask my friends. “You don’t have hayfever, right?” Thankfully, both of them said no. I told myself that as an event planner/organizer, I should take into account this kind of detail. Next time I will try to bear in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the bus ride, I introduced the recently popular word game, Wordle, to Hina. I already exchanged Wordle results with Lai every day so there was no need to introduce it to her. I thought that because Hina is interested in English, she would enjoy Wordle. I explained the game rules to her and she started guessing the word of the day. If you’re interested in Wordle, you can play it here (I have Japanese readers, okay?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/games/wordle/index.html&quot;&gt;Wordle - A daily word game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;hiking&quot;&gt;Hiking&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus arrived at Mt. Maku Park, which is located at the foot of the mountain. There was an entrance fee so we lined up and purchased the entrance ticket. The sign at the entrance says that the flowers were only 70% in bloom. Too bad, I thought. But I remembered that I was supposed to go here two weeks ago… and if I did, I probably wouldn’t haven’t seen a single flower, so I guess I could still call myself lucky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/PXL_20220226_005856303.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/PXL_20220226_010135586.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were greeted by the pink scenery as we entered the park. Because of the ongoing event, it was more crowded than I expected. There was a bazaar as well. We could have bought our picnic food there, but too bad we already had our convenience store food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/DSC04369.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We approached the foot of the mountain and started hiking. The plum grove was beautiful. I smelled the sweet aroma of the plum blossoms. “Wow it smells so good,” I exclaimed to my friends. However, both of them said they did not smell anything. Ahem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/DSC04381.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we continued walking, we warmed up, basking in the sweltering sunlight. Winter was about to end so it was starting to get warm, I thought. I stripped my warm layers one by one until I was just wearing my shirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We continued walking by just following the path without looking at the map. As we proceeded, the plum trees got fewer and fewer. Huh, that’s strange, I thought, so I checked with my hiking app. “Oh, sh*t, we’re going clockwise” (re: the hiking course was circular and the guide stated that we should go counterclockwise.) I apologized to my friends and asked them whether we should continue or go back. They said it was okay to continue so we did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/Untitled%201.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw this small shrine at the entrance of the forest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We entered a forest of just camphor trees and took another selfie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/PXL_20220226_014026070.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said earlier, it was quite warm today so it felt good to be under the cool shade of the forest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While hiking, Hina exclaimed “oh I have a Wordle guess” and I found it funny, good to know she’s enjoying the game I introduced to her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we continued climbing the forest, the ground started getting muddy. It was slippery and dangerous so we had to be careful. After a few minutes of walking, I realized the reason for the muddiness. We began seeing splotches of thin ice on the ground. That’s when it clicked to me. I saw that this mountain was covered in snow a few days ago on Instagram. So all this mud is probably due to melted snow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/PXL_20220226_032415961.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sign for the mountain summit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally arrived at the top of the mountain. There were many people doing picnic, and we joined them. We set up the picnic mat that I prepared on top of the grass and sat on it. We enjoyed the food that we bought from the convenience store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We noticed that our shoes and pants were so dirty because of the muddy trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While eating, Hina finally solved the Wordle of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/PXL_20220226_024759090.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After eating, we enjoyed the view of Sagami Bay from the top of the mountain. It was nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/DSC04390.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started going down the mountain and it was naturally easier because of gravity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw a huge boulder on the way down, and apparently, people use it for rock climbing. I got excited just by looking at it. Unfortunately, I was not able to try it because I didn’t prepare. Adventurous activities thrill me so I’ll definitely try this kind of rock climbing next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/DSC04398.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked for a bit and we finally arrived back at the plum grove. There were thousands of flowers and it was the definition of a pink forest. I took several pictures using the camera that I brought. Here are some of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/DSC04431.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/DSC04405.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/DSC04429.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-02-26-makuyama/DSC04410.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because there were thousands of them, the fragrance of the plum blossoms was so perceivable. Hina said she was finally able to smell it. The ambrosial fragrance made it seem like we were in paradise. Lai said she still could not smell it. I found it funny that she did not smell any plum blossom during the whole hike. Too bad, I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;going-home&quot;&gt;Going Home&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used Tokyo-Ueno Line again to go home. We were fairly tired so it was a silent train ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I thought that it was such a girly hike, and I love it. The mountain was not high, the hiking trail was friendly, and the scenery was so pink so it’s perfect for a girls’ day out, I thought. I had fun introducing my two friends to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>/makuyama/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/makuyama/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>Hiking</category>
        
        <category>Friends</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Retreat to Kamakura</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to Kamakura for a small retreat from my busy Tokyo life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-first-day&quot;&gt;The First Day&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These few days, the things I need to do and the things I want to do piled up so my mind is so cluttered, making me feel blue. I knew I was gonna burn up anytime soon if I don’t take a break. I didn’t wanna burn out so, to re-organize my thoughts and refresh my mind, I applied for some of my paid leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, I decided to go to Kamakura, which I’ve already visited in the past. I usually want to visit places where I haven’t visited but let me tell you why I chose Kamakura. There are three main reasons. First, Kamakura’s location is not that far from where I live. It just takes an hour to go there. This trip is quite abrupt so I didn’t wanna spend much money so I decided to save on transportation expenses. Second, I chose Kamakura for its vibe. It seems to be a very peaceful place with plenty of temples. It being spiritual suits my current situation, I thought. I’m not a religious person but I like the idea of cleansing one’s soul. The third reason is that Kamakura is situated near the sea. I don’t see seas often so I wanted to go to one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally arrived at Kamakura. I kept my earphones away so I can keep my mind distraction-free&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/0.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting out of Kita-Kamakura station, I saw my first temple of the day, Engakuji.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(By the way, “ji” or “tera” or “dera” means “temple” in Japanese. I feel iffy typing “Engakuji Temple” even though that’s probably the official(?) English translation, because it literally means Engaku-temple Temple)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entrance had a fee so I decided not to go in and just look from the outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked towards my next stopover, Kenchoji, following the signs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hiking course that I planned to take was inside Kenchoji so I had no choice but to enter it, even though it was paid. The temple ground was pretty vast. However, because it was a weekday, there were only very few people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the map, I stumbled upon this remarkably long path. This scene feels like a gate to heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw a few caves while walking. Although I wasn’t sure if I could enter them, they made me excited as they reminded me of my favorite game, Tomb Raider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so intrigued by these statues. I didn’t know what they are but they remind me of angels from Christianity(?) because of their wings. Their whole composition made me feel like they were a mixture of Japan’s tradition and Western. Upon checking on Google, I found out that they were tengu, supernatural beings in Japanese folklore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/10.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/11.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the viewing deck of Hansobo, the heart of Kenchoji.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look close, you can see the sea from afar. I like the fact that I was able to capture temples, forests, hills, and the sea all in one picture. Isn’t it amazing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/12.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/13.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entrance to the hiking course was somewhat blocked so I thought it was closed. Thankfully, the person from the temple shop called out to me and told me that only parts of the hiking trail were closed. Well, I planned to just do some parts of the trail and head to Kamakura station so I proceeded and she let me enter the trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started climbing the hiking course, I saw Mt. Fuji’s iconic white top. The sky was not clear so that part looks like it was floating. Can you spot it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/14.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’m hiking, let me tell you why I enjoy it a lot. When I was still in grade school, I used to play Tomb Raider a lot. I wanted to be like the main character in the game, Lara Croft because she is so strong and adventurous. She often went outdoors to hike and camp, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw a fellow hiker. Japanese hikers are generally friendly so we greeted each other Konnichiwa!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He told me that he can see Mt. Fuji from where he was standing. I already knew I could see Mt. Fuji but he convinced me to go to where he was standing. I went and realized what he was talking about. Mt. Fuji was placed directly on top of the rock, and it was such a good frame to capture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/15.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hiking-thoughts&quot;&gt;Hiking thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While I was hiking, I started to take notice of the minute things again. For example, as the wind blew, I heard the sound of the rustling leaves. Noticing small details of nature like this made me feel the beauty of living in the world.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hiking is free of distraction, that’s why I like it so much. Being in nature is an escape from the busyness of my city life. I feel refreshed by basking in the green forest. This is the feeling of Shinrin-yoku (a Japanese term for forest bathing). I started having doubts about why I chose to live in such a busy city like Tokyo when I prefer a more laid-back place.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I feel grateful living in Japan. First, it is very commuter-friendly. I can easily commute to places such as this without needing a car. Second, because it is not a tropical country, I can do physical activities like hiking without suffering from the heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maybe I also like hiking because it makes me feel closer to death. One wrong step and I could fall and land somewhere inaccessible and no one may know it. So, it means that I could die without anyone knowing. However, I think that being close to death makes me value my life more because I am reminded that I am merely human and not an eternal being. So I want to cherish the time that I have when I’m still alive. It makes me question whether the things I’m doing now are fulfilling my life. Because I only have one life, and after all, I’m a “being towards death”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hiking also makes me feel like I’m in such a huge world because the scenery is so different from my everyday life. And this feeling of being a small entity in an enormous place, such as the world, is not something I feel in my daily life. Suddenly, all my problems and stressors feel so small and insignificant in this huge world. This thought comforts me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve also noticed that there are many older people in this hike. It’s just an amazing thing for me that Japanese elder people are still very strong and healthy that they can do hiking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I passed by this small climb with a rope. Even though it’s such a small thing, it excited me a little because it feels a bit more adventurous. It made me wish I could go to a more adventurous place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/16.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw this lovely hiking couple. Because I wanted to just relax, and not think about navigating myself, I just followed them. Seeing them made me want to have a partner whom I can hike with, even as we grow old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/17.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the end, there were some bamboo groves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/18.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing my fairly short hiking course, I visited Kakuonji (temple) which is situated near the end of the trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/19.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/20.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/21.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/22.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While walking towards Kamakura station, I saw these yellow flowers in bloom, called Wintersweet (ろうばい). They look like yellow cherry blossoms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/23.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;late-lunch&quot;&gt;Late Lunch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was hungry when I finished the long hike and walk. As my holiday treat, I went to a fairly highly rated Japanese restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/24.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ate this and it tasted good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some other photos I took while walking around Kamakura.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/25.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring is about to come!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/26.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/27.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the statues are wearing a mask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heading-towards-my-lodging&quot;&gt;Heading towards my lodging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hostel is located in Hase Station, a few stations away from Kamakura station via the Enoden line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived at my hostel and had a great chat with the friendly hostel owner, Hide-san. He had several recommendations for things to do or restaurants to eat at. And that includes going to Hasedera. I already went to some temples in the morning so I was hesitant to go to another one. However, I still went because I didn’t have anything to do anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hasedera&quot;&gt;Hasedera&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After arriving at the temple grounds and spending a few minutes, I realized that I didn’t regret my decision to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the main hall, the Buddha is not the usual one. It’s gold and huge. I wanted to take a picture but sadly it was prohibited to take photos inside the main hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/28.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/29.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a statue of Amitabha, the Buddha of Limitless Light, in the hall beside the main hall. It is not as big as the main one, but still majestic nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also intrigued by the small statues surrounding one of the halls of Hasedera. Apparently, they are called Sentai Jizo, which means a thousand Jizo’s. According to the guide, Jizo is a Buddhist deity for protecting children and giving prosperity to one’s descendants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/30.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t noticed but when I shared this photo to my friend, he noticed that each face was different from each other. Amazing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the top of the temple grounds and approached the viewing deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/31.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see the town and the sea. It was such a spectacular view. While admiring it, I felt solitude too because there were no other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw some plum blossoms in bloom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/32.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Japanese gardens or temple grounds relaxed me because of wabi-sabi, a form of traditional Japanese beauty which accepts transience and imperfection. I like the concept because it eases my perfectionism, relieving the pressure on things to be perfect. That pressure is lifted as I walk through this garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/33.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to the east of the temple grounds and proceeded to this cave with a tori gate in front. Inside it was so solemn and I felt awe in this very spiritual place.  Few people were praying inside. The temple closed shortly after I exited the cave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/34.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dinner&quot;&gt;Dinner&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my visit to Hasedera, almost everything was closed, so I decided to go to the Izakaya (a Japanese bar) recommended by Hide-san called Shamoji.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/35.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m beside the sea, so it’s just natural for me to eat seafood. I ordered Misaki maguro (tuna) rice bowl with shirasu (whitebait) toppings. Eating this reminds me of the time I went to Misaki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/36.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/37.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fish was fresh as I expected. And I felt full from my rice bowl. So I decided to walk it off before heading back to my hotel. Without realizing it, I reached Kamakura station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/38.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked so much today and I don’t want to arrive at my hotel too late at night, so instead of walking, I decided to take the Enoden line train to Hase station again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived at my hotel quite tired. But, I maximized my day so I won’t complain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-second-day&quot;&gt;The Second Day&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought that since Kamakura is facing East, where the sun will rise, I wanted to see it for myself. I was picking where I want to greet the sun: at the top of a hike, or by the sea while running. I was already tired last night and I didn’t have the energy to look for a trail anymore, so I decided to just go for a run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up around 5:30 am. I drank the free coffee provided by the hostel to energize myself for my run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went outside when it was still dark and started running along the seaside. I loved the sound of the waves and the fresh air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t run seriously, as I was distracted by the beautiful view. I sometimes paused to take videos or photos, which I will dump on this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first stop was Inamuragasaki, a cape not so far from my hostel. I went down to the rocks beside the sea to get a closer view. The waves were roaring as they crashed upon the rocks. I even got showered a bit, which made me laugh. It was so fun yet so calming. I loved the feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/39.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was running towards Enoshima, the sun finally peeked out, so I observed it and snapped a few pictures. The orange rising sun contrasts well with the blue sea. Its light was even reflected by the sea. I felt like I really am in Japan, as I am in the “land of the rising sun,” haha. The view (and the run) was breathtaking, and I felt so lucky to be able to witness a beautiful scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/40.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some pictures from my run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/41.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/42.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enoshima from afar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued running and finally reached Enoshima Ohashi, a bridge towards Enoshima. I wasn’t intending to go to the actual island but I thought since I’m already here, might as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/43.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran from the entrance of Enoshima towards the back part, where the Iwaya Cave is. The island was almost empty because it was an early morning of a weekday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/44.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached the distinct red bridge that leads towards the caves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/45.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the cave doesn’t open until 9 am so I wasn’t able to go in. But it’s okay, I went there twice last year anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran back towards the nearest Enoden station and went back to my hostel to check out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/46.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started heading home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was hungry so I stopped by Kamakura station for brunch. I ate at a cafe called Garden House. I liked its refreshing vibe. Because I was quite hungry, I ordered a salad to add to my open-faced chicken sandwich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-28-kamakura-enoshima/47.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I went back to Tokyo for real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crowd increased as I neared Tokyo. When I finally get off my train, it was pretty crowded. I forgot for a while that Tokyo is a very populated place.  It pricked my heart a bit to be reminded of the busyness of city life. It made me think whether I would rather live in the suburb or provincial place, sacrificing convenience over laid-backness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I arrived home, it felt like I was gone for a very long time. I think it means that I made full use of my two days one night holiday. I did many things, and I was alone. Being alone with my thoughts the whole time, helped me hear my intuition/my heart, which I probably neglected recently. That being said, I think my very cluttered brain came home more organized. In a sense, I fulfilled the purpose of taking a paid leave.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>/kamakura-enoshima/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kamakura-enoshima/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My First Japanese Calligraphy Experience</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I experienced Japanese calligraphy (shodo) for the first time last Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like writing by hand but up until now, I haven’t held a real calligraphy brush so I was excited to join this workshop. Both my friend Yoshiki-san and I wanted to do a new year-ish activity so we thought it would be nice to do Kakizome, the Japanese term for the first writing of the year. Yoshiki-san kindly invited me to this workshop and he registered online for both of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;workshop-day&quot;&gt;Workshop Day&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to eat lunch together before the workshop so we met at Azabujuban Station around an hour before. We ate at a nearby cafe, with a pretty good vibe I liked. The matcha that I ordered tasted better than the one I make at home so I savored it well. As usual, it was fun chatting with Yoshiki-san.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked a bit and we reached a place called エナジーテラスSunnyGo!. It had an art gallery in an underground room roughly as small as my apartment. Though it was small, the atmosphere was lively and colorful, making the cafe I visited earlier pales in comparison. That’s mostly because of the calligrapher’s vibrant art pieces hung all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-26-first-shodo/展示.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Exhibit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-calligrapher&quot;&gt;The Calligrapher&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The calligrapher’s name is Kisen Kuzuya. Based on what I saw in the art gallery, there’s no doubt that Kisen-san is highly-skilled and passionate about Japanese calligraphy (shodo). She said that apart from her main job at an IT company, she makes time to do shodo, explaining that it is not a “side job” but rather a “double job.” (In Japanese, the word for side job is 副業 or fukugyo. Changing the first Kanji or Chinese character to 複, the meaning changes to “multiple jobs” while retaining the reading. Nice wordplay, right?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was deeply moved by that explanation. Kisen-san knowing what she wants and actually doing it inspired me a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;shodo-experience&quot;&gt;Shodo Experience&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said above, I had no prior experience with shodo. So naturally, I was nervous at first. Thankfully, Kisen-san explained the process starting from the basic things, such as explaining the tools used for shodo, how to dip the brush, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It felt nice when I started writing. I fell in love with the feeling of painting the Kanji on the special calligraphy paper. It’s my first time so the character that I wrote was out of balance and kind of looked bad. Kisen-san kindly taught me how to improve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-26-first-shodo/希望.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Learning shodo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One example that I remember is when she taught me that one part of the word for “hope” needed to be curved and not straight as I wrote it to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it was my first time, the creative part of my brain was definitely stimulated. I love the feeling of being creative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-special-present&quot;&gt;A Special Present&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the workshop ended, Kisen-san reminded us that the workshop admission that we had included a present from her. That is, a kanji which Kisen-san thinks represents the participant written by herself on a small card. When Kisen-san was about to write the kanji, all three of us gathered around her. At first, she chose to write the kanji for me first. We tried to guess what she was about to write. When she started writing, the room filled with our oohs and ahhs as we were amazed by her technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Kanji for me was “楽”, which can mean fun or ease. I enjoy my life, so I think it suits me well. And recently, I wanted to feel at ease, so it’s perfect. Yoshiki’s was was “繋”, meaning to connect. The reason is that Yoshiki-san often contacted Kisen-san before this event was held.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took a picture with Kisen-san, holding our presents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-01-26-first-shodo/プレゼント.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our present&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kisen’s kanji is truly a work of art. I couldn’t wait to decorate my home with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I enjoyed experiencing Japanese culture such as shodo. Thanks to the calligrapher Kisen-san’s bubbly personality, we also felt cheerful. I learned many things about shodo, making me want to write more kanji characters in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>/first-shodo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/first-shodo/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Culture</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spending my winter holidays in Nagano</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to spend my holidays in a snowy place so I went to Nagano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-day-before&quot;&gt;The Day Before&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished packing my pack the day before. My backpack was pretty big so I also slipped my whole camera bag inside it. I haven’t worn the white boots in the picture for two years already so I was excited as I was going to be able to wear them again on this trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/前日-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bag&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, I haven’t been to a snowy place for two years already. I checked the weather forecast to mentally prepare for that. It seems that it will be freezing so I was a bit nervous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/前日-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;Weather forecast&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will leave at 6 am the next day so I set my alarm to 5 am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/前日-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alarm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-first-day&quot;&gt;The First Day&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s go! It was still dark but I wanted to make full use of the day so I decided to leave early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/一日目-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Train&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, I was going to meet with my company for this trip at Ueno Station’s Shinkansen (bullet train) platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thoughts while commuting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I completely forgot, but today is a weekday! I shouldn’t have been surprised to be on such a packed train…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;riding-the-shinkansen-from-ueno-station&quot;&gt;Riding the Shinkansen from Ueno Station&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was finally able to meet with my friend. We wanted to buy tickets from the ticket sales machine but I used Mobile Suica (IC Card), I could not use it, for the machine only accepts the physical card. So, we ended up buying from the ticket office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/上野駅-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Shinkansen platform&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/上野駅-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Shinkansen platform&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introducing-my-friend&quot;&gt;Introducing my Friend&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Name: Bryan Lao&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nickname: Bry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/友達の紹介-00.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bry and I&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bry was my instructor for programming in my alma mater, Ateneo. He graduated as a PhD student in NAIST. He moved to Tokyo after that after that to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chat-in-the-shinkansen&quot;&gt;Chat in the Shinkansen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difference between Philippine and Japanese culture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We both grew up in the Philippines and came to Japan in our 20s. We compared and discussed how it is different to live in the Philippines and Japan and the different points of view which both countries can be looked at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trying out camera lenses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/カメラレンズ-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Camera&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bry is a camera enthusiast so he owns several camera lenses. He lent me one to use with my mirrorless camera, explaining its capabilities and usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;arriving-at-nagano-station&quot;&gt;Arriving at Nagano Station&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the Shinkansen, in just a few hours, we arrived at Nagano Station. It’s way colder here than in Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/長野駅-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nagano Station&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-learned-about-sugitama&quot;&gt;I learned about Sugitama&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While looking for a place to eat breakfast, Bry called out to me. He pointed to the green sphere hanging from the ceiling, explaining that it is called a Sugitama (“cedar ball”, indicating the maturity of sake. Green balls are freshly made sake, which develops into brown balls that are matured sake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/杉玉-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sugitama&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breakfast-at-kobeya-kitchen&quot;&gt;Breakfast at Kobeya Kitchen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ordered a hot sandwich set. Traveling is no excuse not to eat veggies so I was glad that my order came with a side salad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/神戸屋-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Breakfast&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heading-towards-yudanaka-station&quot;&gt;Heading towards Yudanaka Station&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can choose between riding a bus or a train but the bus makes me nauseous so we decided to take the train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/湯田中駅に向かう-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Heading towards Yudanaka Station&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was surprised that I could not use my Suica in this station. So, I bought from the ticket sales machine again (☉｡☉)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/湯田中駅に向かう-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ticket&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought it was strange that the train floor was wet. And then I realized that it was probably due to all the snow from the passengers’ shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took this picture on my train transfer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/湯田中駅に向かう-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;Train&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The views we had in our train ride were fields and mountains blanketed by thick snow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/湯田中駅に向かう-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;View&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;arriving-at-our-hostel&quot;&gt;Arriving at Our Hostel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our room was a simple traditional Japanese-style room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/ホテル-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Room&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outside view was also Japanese style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/ホテル-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Outside view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lunch&quot;&gt;Lunch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ate Pork Char siu Ramen at a small Chinese diner behind our hostel. We planned to walk lots so eating something full of carbs was justly appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/ランチ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lunch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got full from this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jigokudani-monkey-park&quot;&gt;Jigokudani Monkey Park&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch, we headed towards Jigokudani Monkey Park, a park where you can see monkeys bathe in onsen (hot spring). We walked on a snow-covered mountain road. There was snow everywhere I looked and everything was so white and pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/地獄谷野猿公苑-00.png&quot; alt=&quot;Walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The road was thickly covered with fresh snow so they were so soft to walk at. It was surprising that there was no one else here, despite being a tourist spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/地獄谷野猿公苑-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After walking for so long, we finally arrived at the park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monkeys weren’t inside the onsen, but rather just sitting or walking around. Maybe because they can access the onsen anytime, they’re probably tired of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/地獄谷野猿公苑-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;Monkey park&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes, finally one of them entered the onsen, delighting the visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/地獄谷野猿公苑-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Monkey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from that, these two monkeys did something funny. Bry said that I was able to take the “perfect picture” lol&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/地獄谷野猿公苑-04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Monkey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to walk back from the monkey park back to our hostel. The ramen I ate was already fully digested so I was hungry again. Luckily, there was a cafe halfway on the way home. The cafe’s lighting charmingly contrasts with the winter scenery so I decided to take this picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/ココアのお店.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cafe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ordered hot chocolate, which is perfect for winter, am I right? ( ꈍᴗꈍ)
Because of the warmth that it gave me, I was able to conquer the cold snowy mountain on the way back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/ココア.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cocoa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;yudanaka-onsen&quot;&gt;Yudanaka Onsen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hostel we stayed at was affiliated with an onsen called Yorozuya, so we were able to purchase onsen tickets at a discounted price. We headed to the said onsen, which was just a 5-minute walk from our hostel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/湯田中温泉-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yorozuya&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/湯田中温泉-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yorozuya&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two words to describe Yorozuya’s interior were elegant and traditional. I love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/湯田中温泉-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yorozuya&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/湯田中温泉-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yorozuya&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I entered the rotenburo (“open-air hot spring bath”) and admired the snow surrounding it. It’s the second-best onsen experience I had (the first one was when it was actually snowing). My exhausted feet which I used the whole day was revitalized, thanks to the heat of the onsen. Entering the onsen is the best feeling for the tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bry was this happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip//湯田中温泉-04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bry in onsen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dinner-at-the-izakaya&quot;&gt;Dinner at the Izakaya&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was already late we left the onsen so almost all of the restaurants were already closed. We ended up eating at an Izakaya (Japanese bar).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/居酒屋-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Izakaya&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bry has an alcohol allergy and I wanted to reduce my alcohol intake so both of us ordered soft drinks only at the Izakaya (lol). I thought it was funny when said cheers over our glasses of orange juice and soda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/居酒屋-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Soft drinks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ate yakitori. It was so salty, so thank god I ordered orange juice to save my tongue lol&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/居酒屋-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yakitori&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t tried Yakionigiri (grilled rice ball) so I ordered it as well. I thought its brown color was because of using brown rice, making me amazed how such a healthy menu can be ordered in a bar. However, Bry said that it wasn’t brown rice, but rather due to soy sauce. Oops. (；^ω^）&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/居酒屋-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;焼きおにぎり&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-second-day&quot;&gt;The Second Day&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;okushiga-kogen-ski-resort&quot;&gt;Okushiga Kogen Ski Resort&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used this discounted red ticket to go to Okushiga Kogen Ski Resort by bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/奥志賀高原-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The snow-covered mountain is so pretty, right? This is the kind of view that I couldn’t see in Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/奥志賀高原-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Snow view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bought ski lift tickets and rented some skis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/奥志賀高原-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rental&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/奥志賀高原-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rental&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/奥志賀高原-04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rode the lift. Thankfully the weather was good ヽ(･ˇ∀ˇ･ゞ)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/奥志賀高原-05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lift&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t take ski school or class so we were naturally not good at it. I watched the other skiers and tried to copy them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was very scared but I really wanted to try skiing. Once I got off the lift, there was no other way to go down but to ski. I tried to use my earphones to mask my fear. And it worked, the lively music alleviated my fear a bit, encouraging me to go down the slope. In fact, it excited me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I often lost my confidence. I was afraid to fall so I panicked a lot. Because of that panic, my body stiffened, making me end up falling. I can’t even count how many times I fell, I just knew it was too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was quite embarrassing because I’m so bad at it despite being on a beginner slope (^～^;)ゞ. But it’s okay, I assured myself. It’s only reasonable because everyone is a beginner at first. Anyway, my purpose for skiing was to have fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair, I had a lot of fun. Even falling several times was okay because the snow was very soft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But doing something you’re unfamiliar with is tiring, right? What I want to say is skiing fried my brain too (~_~メ)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heading-towards-shibu-onsen&quot;&gt;Heading towards Shibu Onsen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the same ticket, we went down the hill via bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/渋温泉へ-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Same ticket&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dinner&quot;&gt;Dinner&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking a bit from the bus stop, we arrived at a restaurant called Happy Restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/ハッピー-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Happy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, some real food here! (Btw, my breakfast was just yogurt and my lunch was just Calorie Mate, a Japanese brand energy bar).
The tonkatsu (pork cutlet) set that I ordered was quite good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/ハッピー-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tonkatsu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kanaguya&quot;&gt;Kanaguya&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We visited Shibu Onsen’s Kanaguya on the way home. It is a historical Japanese inn that inspired Studio Ghibli’s Spirited Away, they say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/金具屋-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kanaguya&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started to walk back home from Shibu Onsen. Some snow was already half melted so it was very slippery. We threaded carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While walking, I saw this snow-covered post. Snow and posts are two things I like so I was glad to take this picture. The vivid red post has a beautiful contrast with the muted white snow, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/金具屋-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Post&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-last-day&quot;&gt;The Last Day&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We checked out and headed to Yudanaka Station. From there, we took the train to go to Nagano Station. I wanted to kill time so I read a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/三日目-00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Reading a book&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was lunchtime when we arrived. Bry wanted to eat Shinshu Soba so we ate at a standing soba restaurant at the station. I ordered soba with egg. Note that this was my first time eating at a standing restaurant (人 •͈ᴗ•͈)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/三日目-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Soba&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was time for us to ride the bus that we reserved so we headed to the bus stop. We’re taking the bus on the way home because we wanted to save. But vacations are supposed to be enjoyed, so we didn’t want to cheap out too much. The good compromise would be taking the shinkansen on the way to, and the bus on the way back, we thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/三日目-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read again inside the bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-12-30-nagano-winter-trip/三日目-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;本を読んでいる&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I finished writing this report. Overall, these past three days have been a lovely way to spend my vacation. This is the longest time I’ve walked on snow. As a Filipino, I grew up in a tropical country where there isn’t snow so going to a snowy place such as Nagano made me glad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>/nagano-winter-trip/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/nagano-winter-trip/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
